<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership on </title>
    <link>http://thejoemorgan.com/categories/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leadership on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 14:23:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://thejoemorgan.com/categories/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ways Coders Lead</title>
      <link>http://thejoemorgan.com/2016/03/08/ways-coders-lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 14:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thejoemorgan.com/2016/03/08/ways-coders-lead/</guid>
      <description>I spend a lot of time thinking about how people lead. And when I say that, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean how people manage. I want to know how effective people make things happen. Sometimes they are also managers. Sometimes they are not.
Of course, I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one, there has been an ocean of ink spilled on the topic. There is less, though, specifically about ways that coders can lead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I love Microtraining</title>
      <link>http://thejoemorgan.com/2015/11/17/why-i-love-micro-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 08:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thejoemorgan.com/2015/11/17/why-i-love-micro-training/</guid>
      <description>Training is important. Nearly every job, nearly every department, nearly every company will at least tacitly acknowledge importance of training.
However, the effectiveness training when it is implemented is limited. Why? Because nearly always, the training involves long periods in a room with someone yammering on for at least an hour (and often much, much longer). The ideas are useful but often too abstract for any attendants particular needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interviews Are About the Future Not The Past</title>
      <link>http://thejoemorgan.com/2015/03/18/interviews-are-about-the-future-not-the-past/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 14:12:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thejoemorgan.com/2015/03/18/interviews-are-about-the-future-not-the-past/</guid>
      <description>##Most Interviews Are Horrible It&amp;rsquo;s almost a cliché to point out how a lot of common business practices are carried on out of sense of familiarity or tradition without any thought about what they are trying to accomplish
Job interviews are one of the worst.
I&amp;rsquo;ve interviewed many people and have been interviewed many times to the point that the pattern is so easy I could repeat it in my sleep:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leading Without Authority</title>
      <link>http://thejoemorgan.com/2015/01/27/leading-without-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 16:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thejoemorgan.com/2015/01/27/leading-without-authority/</guid>
      <description>I have never had one of those positions where people had to do what I say or else! Honestly, I think that has been for the best because with very few exceptions most of us will not have authority over someone we are trying to persuade; we can&amp;rsquo;t tell our boss to do it our way or else. Even in cases where we do have authority over a person or a group of people, the moment we start invoking that authority as a means of changed, we have already failed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>